References
Best, H., Dannwolf, T., 2019. GESIS Panel Core Study – zd: Environmental attitudes and behavior. https://doi.org/10.4232/1.12045
Best, H., & Kroneberg, C. (2012). Die Low-Cost-Hypothese. Kölner Zeitschrift für Soziologie und Sozialpsychologie, 64(3), 535-561.
Chatzidakis, A., Hibbert, S., Smith, A.P., 2007. Why people don’t take their concerns about fair trade to the supermarket: The role of neutralisation. J. Bus. ethics 74, 89–100.
Diekmann, A., Preisendörfer, P., 2003. Green and Greenback The Behavioral Effects of Environmental Attitudes in Low-Cost and High-Cost Situations. Ration. Soc. 15, 441–472.
Festinger, L., 1954. A Theory of Social Comparison Processes. Hum. Relations 7, 117–140.
Gruber, V., Schlegelmilch, B.B., 2014. How techniques of neutralization legitimize norm-and attitude-inconsistent consumer behavior. J. Bus. ethics 121, 29–45.
Keuschnigg, M., Kratz, F., 2018. Thou shalt recycle: How social norms of environmental protection narrow the scope of the low-cost hypothesis. Environ. Behav. 50, 1059–1091.
Schahn, J., Dinger, J., Bohner, G., 1995. Rationalisierungen und Neutralisationen als Rechtfertigungsstrategien: Ein Vergleich zwischen Uumwelt-und Delinquenzbereich. mental 18, 451–460.
Steg, L., Bolderdijk, J.W., Keizer, K., Perlaviciute, G., 2014. An integrated framework for encouraging pro-environmental behaviour: The role of values, situational factors and goals. J. Environ. Psychol. 38, 104–115.
Sykes, G.M., Matza, D., 1957. Techniques of neutralization: A theory of delinquency. Am. Sociol. Rev. 22, 664–670.
Tam, K.-P., Chan, H.-W., 2017. Environmental concern has a weaker association with pro-environmental behavior in some societies than others: A cross-cultural psychology perspective. J. Environ. Psychol. 53, 213–223.
Thiel, F. (2020). Die Low-Cost-Hypothese. Ein empirischer Test am Beispiel der Befürwortung einer City-Maut. KZfSS Kölner Zeitschrift für Soziologie und Sozialpsychologie, 72(3), 429-453.
Tutić, A., Voss, T., & Liebe, U. (2017). Low-Cost-Hypothese und Rationalität. KZfSS Kölner Zeitschrift für Soziologie und Sozialpsychologie, 69(4), 651-672.
Uba, C.D., Chatzidakis, A., 2016. Understanding engagement and disengagement from pro-environmental behaviour: The role of neutralization and affirmation techniques in maintaining persistence in and desistance from car use. Transp. Res. part A Policy Pract. 94, 278–294.

